<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
  <properties>
    <title>Mappings</title>
    <author email="fgarsombke@yahoo.com">Franz Garsombke</author>
  </properties>
  <head>
    <title/>
    <meta http-equiv="CACHE-CONTROL" name="CACHE-CONTROL" content="NO-CACHE"/>
    <meta http-equiv="PRAGMA" name="PRAGMA" content="NO-CACHE"/>
    <meta http-equiv="EXPIRES" content="0"/>
  </head>
  <body>
    <section name="Custom Mappings Via Dozer XML Files">
      <p>
        This section will cover setting up custom mappings in xml file(s). If the two different types of data
        objects that you are mapping contain any fields that don't share a common property name, you will need to
        add a class mapping entry to your custom mapping xml file. These mappings xml files are used at runtime by
        the Dozer mapping engine.
      </p>
      <p>
        Dozer automatically performs any type conversion when copying the source field data to the destination
        field. The Dozer mapping engine is bi-directional, so if you wanted to map the destination object to the
        source object, you do not need to add another class mapping to the xml file.

      </p>
      <p>An example of a mapping file....</p>
      <source>
        <![CDATA[ 
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<mappings xmlns="http://dozer.sourceforge.net"
          xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
          xsi:schemaLocation="http://dozer.sourceforge.net
          http://dozer.sourceforge.net/schema/beanmapping.xsd">
          
  <mapping> 
    <class-a>org.dozer.vo.TestObject</class-a>
    <class-b>org.dozer.vo.TestObjectPrime</class-b>   
    <field>
      <a>one</a>
      <b>onePrime</b>
    </field>
  </mapping>  

  <mapping wildcard="false"> 
    <class-a>org.dozer.vo.TestObjectFoo</class-a>
    <class-b>org.dozer.vo.TestObjectFooPrime</class-b>   
      <field>
        <a>oneFoo</a>
        <b>oneFooPrime</b>
      </field>
  </mapping>  

</mappings>
        ]]>
      </source>
      <p>
        A mappings element has multiple mapping elements, each with class mapping declarations and field level
        mappings. The wildcard attribute is set to true by default. This means that it will automatically try to
        map every property in the two objects. When the attribute is set to false it will only map explicitly
        defined fields.
      </p>
      <p>
        <b>IMPORTANT:</b>
        Properties that are of the same name do not need to be specified in the mapping xml file. Dozer
        automatically maps all fields with the same property name from the source object into the destination
        object.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section name="How Custom Mapping Files Are Loaded">
      <p>Dozer will search the entire classpath looking for the specified file. The generally acceptable way of
      distributing your mappings is to bundle them inside your application archive.</p>
      <p>
        Alternatively, you can load files from outside the classpath by prepending "file:" to the resource name.
        Ex) "file:c:\somedozermapping.xml"
      </p>
    </section>

  </body>
</document>