<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="fgarsombke@yahoo.com">Franz Garsombke</author>
    <title>about</title>
  </properties>
  <head>
    <meta http-equiv="CACHE-CONTROL" name="CACHE-CONTROL" CONTENT="NO-CACHE"/>    
    <meta http-equiv="PRAGMA" name="PRAGMA" CONTENT="NO-CACHE"/>      
    <META HTTP-EQUIV="EXPIRES" CONTENT="0"/>    
  </head>  
  <body>
    <section name="Why Map?">
        <p>
          A mapping framework is useful in a layered architecture where you are creating layers 
          of abstraction by encapsulating changes to particular data objects vs. propagating 
          these objects to other layers (i.e. external service data objects, domain objects, data transfer objects, 
          internal service data objects).  A mapping framework is ideal for using within Assembler 
          type classes that are responsible for mapping from one data object to another.
          <br></br>
          For SOA/ESB systems, a side effect is the passing of domain objects between different systems. Typically, you won't want 
          internal domain objects exposed externally and won't allow for external domain objects to bleed 
          into your system.
          <br></br>
          Mapping between data objects has been traditionally addressed by hand coding value object assemblers (or converters) that copy data between the objects.  
          Most programmers will develop some sort of custom mapping framework and spend countless hours and thousands of lines of code mapping to and from their many transfer objects.
          <br></br>
          A generic mapping framework solves these problems.  Dozer is an open source mapping framework that 
          is robust, generic, flexible, reusable, and configurable.
          <br></br>
          Data object mapping is an important part of layered service oriented architectures.  
          Pick and choose the layers you use mapping carefully.  Do not go overboard as there is 
          maintenance and performance costs associated with mapping data objects between layers. 
        </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>