<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Dozer</title>
    <author email="fgarsombke@yahoo.com">Franz Garsombke</author>
  </properties>
  <head>
    <title/>
    <meta http-equiv="Description" name="Description"
          content="Dozer is a powerful, yet simple Java Bean to Java Bean mapper."/>
    <meta http-equiv="Keywords" name="Keywords"
          content="Java Bean Mapper, Java, Mapper, Complex Mapping, Dozer, bean utils, DTO"/>
    <meta http-equiv="CACHE-CONTROL" name="CACHE-CONTROL" content="NO-CACHE"/>
    <meta http-equiv="PRAGMA" name="PRAGMA" content="NO-CACHE"/>
    <meta http-equiv="EXPIRES" content="-1"/>
  </head>
  <body>
    <section name="Dozer">
      <p>
        Dozer is a Java Bean to Java Bean mapper that recursively copies data from one object to another.
        Typically, these Java Beans will be of different complex types.
      </p>
      <p>
        Dozer supports simple property mapping, complex type mapping, bi-directional mapping, implicit-explicit
        mapping, as well as recursive mapping. This includes mapping collection attributes that also need mapping
        at the element level.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please read the
        <a href="documentation/about.html">about</a>
        page for detailed information on Dozer.
      </p>
    </section>
    <section name="Dozer News">
      <p/>

        <h3>Release 5.3.2 Now Available<font size="-3" color="gray"> <i>02/15/2011</i></font></h3>
        <p>
          Release 5.3.2 is available for download. This is maintenance release, which finalizes internal builder API
          implementation and delivers several bugfixes. Experimental annotations support for simple mappings has been
          added.
        </p>
        <p>
          Additionally, thanks to Lenkwe Makhubela, Dozer Eclipse plugin is finally working on Eclipse 3.6.
        </p>
        <p>
          Refer to <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a> for detailed information.
        </p>
        <p/>

        <h3>Release 5.3.1 Now Available<font size="-3" color="gray"> <i>11/15/2010</i></font></h3>
        <p>
            Release 5.3.1 is available for download. This is maintenance release bringing compatibility with
            Apache Camel framework and fixing a few bugs found in 5.3.0.
            Upgrade is highly recommended for 5.3.0 users.
        </p>

        <h3>Release 5.3.0 Now Available<font size="-3" color="gray"> <i>10/10/2010</i></font></h3>
        <p>
            Release 5.3.0 is available for download. This release brings several major changes to Dozer.
            First is migration to SLF4J logging framework. Second is introduction of alternative way of
            providing custom mappings via Java API. In the meanwhile we reached 50000 downloads 
            from the website. This is excluding Maven repository.
        </p>
        <p>
          Refer to <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a> for detailed information.
        </p>
        <p/>

        <h3>Release 5.2.2 Now Available<font size="-3" color="gray"> <i>6/9/2010</i></font></h3>
        <p>
            Release 5.2.2 is available for download. This is a maintenance release fixing
            several issues.
            Upgrade is recommended for all 5.x.x users.
        </p>
        <p>Thanks to everyone contributing for this release!</p>
        <p>
          Please check <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a> for more information.
        </p>
        <p/>


      <h3>Release 5.2.1 Now Available<font size="-3" color="gray"> <i>4/28/2010</i></font></h3>
      <p>
          Release 5.2.1 is available for download. Important new features are Dozer OSGi bundle and
          Expression Language support. Several bugs has been fixed as well.
          Upgrade is recommended for all 5.x.x users.
      </p>
      <p>Thanks to everyone contributing for this release!</p>
      <p>
        Please check <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a> for more information.
      </p>
      <p/>

      <h3>Release 5.2.0 Now Available<font size="-3" color="gray"> <i>1/24/2010</i></font></h3>
      <p>
          Dozer team is happy to announce release 5.2.0. This version fixes fourteen bugs of different kind
          and provides several new features, such as referencing current mapper object inside a custom converter.
          Upgrade is recommended for all 5.x.x users.
      </p>
      <p>Thanks to everyone contributing for this release!</p>
      <p>
        Please check <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a> for more information.
      </p>
      <p/>

      <h3>
        Release 5.1 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>8/25/2009</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This is a maintenance release addressing more than a dozen bugs. Upgrade is recommended
        for everyone using 5.0 version. Several nasty bugs in area of processing complex type
        hierarchies have been fixed. The most valuable addition to this version is a new custom
        converter API, which supports Generics.
      </p>
      <p>Thanks to everyone contributing patches and ideas for this release!</p>
      <p>
        Please check <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a> for more information.
      </p>
      <p/>

      <h3>
        Dozer Eclipse Plugin 0.8.0 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>6/24/2009</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This is the first release with a fully featured GUI around the Mapping XML.
      </p>
      <p>
        Features are:
        <ul>
          <li>GUI for the mapping XML. Based on Eclipse Forms.</li>
          <li>Content Assist and XML Validation for the XML View.</li>
          <li>Compatible with Dozer 4.x and 5.x</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>
        Thanks to Angelo Zerr who wrote the
        <a href="http://wiki.eclipse.org/JFace_Data_Binding/SSE">DOM/SSE Databinding</a>
        that the Plugin uses.
        <br/>
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more information.
        <br/>
        <a href="documentation/eclipse-plugin/installation.html">installation</a>
        <br/>
        <a href="documentation/eclipse-plugin/usage.html">usage</a>
      </p>
      <p/>

      <h3>
        Release 5.0 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>3/3/2009</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This release contains changes that are not backwards compatible with prior versions of Dozer.
        There is a 5.0 migration guide in the
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
        section, which outlines these changes.
      </p>
      <p>
        Key 5.0 changes:
        <ul>
          <li>Added Generics to public api</li>
          <li>Switched to XSD instead of DTD</li>
          <li>Simpler packaging</li>
          <li>Upgraded 3rd party dependencies</li>
          <li>Upgraded code to use jdk 1.5 features</li>
          <li>Various feature requests and bug fixes</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <p>
        Thanks to everyone that helped out with this release and submitted tickets. Please let us know if you find any
        issues with the release and we will do our best to fix them soon as possible.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more information and the 5.0 migration guide.
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p/>

      <h3>
        Release 4.4.1 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>1/31/2009</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>This release fixes classloading issues for custom ClassLoaders. These classloading issues were introduced in
        the 4.3 release.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p/>

      <h3>
        Release 4.4 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>12/27/2008</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>This release contains various bug fixes and feature requests.</p>

      <p>
        Thanks to everyone that submitted bugs and contributed to the release.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p/>

      <h3>
        Release 4.3 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>12/03/2008</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This is a maintenance release targeting mostly bug fixes. Note that this release changes classloading behaviour.
        If you are experiencing classloading problems in any application container, please tell us urgently.
      </p>
      <p>
        Thanks to our contributors for submitted bug reports and patches, which helped greatly during this release
        development.
      </p>
      <p>
        Contributors to the project are more than welcome as usual!
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
        for detailed information.
      </p>

      <p/>
      <h3>
        Release 4.2.1 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>6/22/2008</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>This minor release contains a fix for the stop-on-error bug.</p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>

      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 4.2 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>12/16/2007</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>This release contains various bug fixes.</p>

      <p>
        Thanks to everyone that submitted bugs and contributed to the release.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 4.1 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>09/22/2007</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>This release contains bug fixes and feature requests, along with internal refactoring.</p>

      <p>
        Thanks again to everyone that submitted bug and feature requests, along with everyone that contributed to
        the release.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 4.0 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>07/15/2007</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This release contains bug fixes and feature requests, along with internal refactoring. Some new features
        include indexed mapping within deep mapping, improved support of Map backed properties, and configuration
        of auto string trimming.
      </p>
      <p>
        The most significant refactoring was around Map backed properties. The refactoring did not change the
        public Dozer API or the xml dtd, but if you are currently using the Map backed property features of Dozer
        please thoroughly regression test your system after upgrading to 4.0 to verify that any expected behavior
        remains unchanged for your specific use cases. We do have a good amount of unit tests around the Map backed
        property feature, but please let us know if you experience any issues after upgrading and we will do
        everything we can to resolve it soon as possible.
      </p>
      <p>
        Thanks again to everyone that submitted bug and feature requests, along with everyone that contributed to
        the release.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <p></p>

      <h3>
        Dozer hits 10,000 Downloads
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>05/19/2007</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>
        We released dozer around 2 years ago and never expected this many downloads for such a niche framework.
        Thanks to the community for contributing and using our tool. Let's hope for 10,000 more downloads!
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 3.4 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>05/19/2007</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>This release contains bug fixes and feature requests.</p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 3.3.1 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>04/28/2007</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This release contains improvements to non-cumulative mapping, enhancements to the logic that auto discovers
        default field mappings, bug fixes, and feature requests.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        1,000,000 Project Web Hits
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>04/08/2007</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>The Dozer project recently eclipsed the 1 million hit mark. Thanks everyone! It's been fun.</p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 3.2.1 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>04/08/2007</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This small release contains feature requests for Boolean to Number auto conversion, custom converter
        statistics, and a small performance improvement for jdk1.5 users.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 3.2 Now Available
        <font size="-3" color="gray">
          <i>04/03/2007</i>
        </font>
      </h3>
      <p>This minor release contains bug fixes and feature requests.</p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <p>Thanks to everyone that has submitted new bug and feature requests over the last month.</p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 3.1 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">03/25/2007</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This release contains support for Java 1.5 generics (you no longer need to give hints for typed
        collections!), enums, performance improvements, bug fixes, feature requests, and a move to subversion. This
        release will also be hosted in the Maven 2 Repository.
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <p>
        Thanks again to everyone submitted bug and feature requests, along with everyone that contributed to the
        release.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 3.0 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">02/09/2007</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This release contains infrastructure upgrades, bug fixes, feature requests, and some performance
        improvements.
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <p>
        One thing to note is Custom Converters are now invoked if the src value is null, so just make sure any
        Custom Converters you have created explicitly handle a null source value.
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <p>
        Thanks again to everyone submitted bug and feature requests, along with everyone that contributed to the
        release.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <p></p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 2.4 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">10/16/2006</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This release contains bug fixes and feature requests. One thing to note is that with this release
        RuntimeExceptions will no longer be wrapped in a MappingException. Thanks to everyone submitted
        bugs/feature requests and contributed to the release.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 2.3 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">09/01/2006</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>
        We are back after taking some time to enjoy the unlimited summer activities in the Rockies. This release
        focuses on bug fixes, feature requests, and general cleanup/refactoring of the code base. Thanks to
        everyone that contributed to the release!
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 2.2 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">04/29/2006</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This release includes runtime statistics support, JMX integration, event listening model, dozer
        configuration through a properties file, XMLBeans mapping, and a few other things. There is also a few bug
        fixes.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 2.1 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">04/18/2006</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This release includes indexed mapping support, bi-directional self mapping and much more. There is also a
        few bug fixes.
      </p>
      <p>Thank you Kiersztyn Wojtek and Peciuch Dominic for your index based mapping code contribution!</p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 2.0.1 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">02/02/2006</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>This release had a few new features and a few bug fixes.</p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 2.0 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">01/16/2006</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>
        This release was mainly performance based. We have seen a 400% - 800% increase in mapping performance.
        Check here for our profiling
        <a href="http://sourceforge.net/forum/forum.php?thread_id=1413981&amp;forum_id=452529">notes</a>
        .
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for more
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 1.5.8 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">11/30/2005</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>Removed dependency on Castor. We also added a few more features.</p>
      <p>
        Please check here for
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 1.5.7 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">11/15/2005</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>
        Dozer now supports map-backed properties. This is extremely useful for mapping objects to/from many UI
        frameworks. The next release of Dozer will focus purely on performance enhancements.
      </p>
      <p>
        Please check here for
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Release 1.5.6 Now Available
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">10/31/2005</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>
        Please check here for
        <a href="releasenotes.html">release notes</a>
      </p>
      <p></p>
      <h3>
        Dozer in the Java Developer's Journal!
        <i>
          <font size="-2" color="gray">10/15/2005</font>
        </i>
      </h3>
      <p>
        Dozer is mentioned as a great way to map objects between application layers in the October issue of the
        <a href="http://jdj.sys-con.com/read/140097_p.htm">JDJ</a>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>